# John Henry Joromat

Ozamiz City 7200 jhenryj09@gmail.com +63 938 098 8490

A confident and reliable IT support engineer with extensive practical experience of working with computers and resolving any support issues that are raised to the service desk. Possessing a proven ability to administer and control the operation, configuration, and maintenance of computer-based information systems, as well as having an eye for detail and able to multi-task under pressure. An excellent communicator can relate well with people at all levels and has the flexibility of working well as part of a team and on my own.

# Work Experience

# **It Support Engineer**

CloudConsole IT Consulting - Makati August 2022 to Present

- Provide technical assistance to client end-users.
- Troubleshoot customer workstation issues.
- Proactively monitor and report on client environments.
- Work with Senior Engineers, Team Leads, and Project Managers to troubleshoot client issues as they arise.
- Coordinate with the engineering team and project managers to ensure projects are carried out on time.
- Timely and accurate time log completion (with detailed notes).
- Dependable and regular attendance in the call gueue.
- Proactive daily schedule communication with team members and team leader.
- Ensure proper execution and delivery of software patching, backups, alerts, antivirus, updates, hardware monitoring, ConnectWise products, TPAM, Kaseya, SSL certs, and software.
- Assist with special projects as needed.

#### Front End Web Developer Trainee

VOLENDAY, INC - Makati March 2022 to June 2022

- Meeting with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications.
- Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.
- Identifying web-based user interactions.
- Developing and implementing highly responsive user interface components using React concepts.
- Writing application interface codes using JavaScript following React.js workflows.
- Troubleshooting interface software and debugging application codes.
- Developing and implementing front-end architecture to support user interface concepts.
- Monitoring and improving front-end performance.
- Documenting application changes and developing updates.

### IT Specialist

Pryce Gases, Inc - General Santos November 2019 to September 2020

- Review diagnostics and assess the functionality and efficiency of systems
- Implement security measures
- Offer technical support to company staff and troubleshoot computer problems
- Install and update company software and hardware as needed
- Anticipate and report the cost of replacing or updating computer items
- Resolve office-related issues according to predetermined procedures.

# Education

# **Bachelor of Science in Information Technology**

Ramon Magsaysay Memorial Colleges - General Santos June 2014 to March 2018

# High school diploma

Ozamiz City School of Arts and Trades - Ozamiz City June 2008 to March 2012

# Skills

- · Customer service
- Maintenance
- Communication skills
- Windows Remote Desktop
- Microsoft 365
- · Administrative experience
- Technical support
- Computer skills
- Network support

#### Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-henry-joromat/

# Certifications and Licenses

# **Scientific Computing with Python**

July 2023 to Present

Obtained a certificate from freeCodeCamp.org

# **3CX Basic Certificate**

March 2023 to Present

Obtained a certificate from 3CX

#### Introduction to Generative AI

July 2023 to Present

Obtained a certificate from Google Cloud Skill Boost

# **Generative AI Fundamentals**

July 2023 to Present

Obtained a certificate from Google Skill Cloud Boost

# **HTML & CSS - Certification Course for Beginners**

March 2021 to Present

Obtained a certificate from YouAccel

# **Foundations of Cybersecurity**

July 2023 to Present

Obtained a certificate provided by Google.

# **Introduction to Cyber Security**

September 2023 to Present

Received a Certificate of Completion for successfully completing Introduction to Cyber Security Learning Path from TryHackMe.com

September 16, 2023